Guide to the Secular Yiddish Schools in North America Collection M0732
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Secular Yiddish Schools in North America collection
1915-2013
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Friends of the Secular Yiddish Schools in North America
M0732
68.5 Linear Feet (130 manuscript boxes, 12 flat boxes, 2 oversize folders)
Materials include curricula, newsletters, instruction books, song books, school board minutes, photographs, newsclippings, memoirs, ephemera and correspondence.
Scope and Content of Collection
Materials include curricula, newsletters, instruction books, song books, school board minutes, photographs, newsclippings, memoirs, ephemera and correspondence. The collection is organized into three original series (Series 1. Yiddish School files; Series 2. Audiovisual materials, and Series 3. Artifacts) and a fourth series for material received in the 2011 accession.
Acquisition Information
Gift of many donors, 1994-1998, and of the Friends of the Secular Yiddish Schools in America collection, 1999, 2001, 2002,2003, 2006, 2007 and 2011.
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Yiddish literature.; Jews -- United States.; Jewish studies.; Textbooks.; Jews -- Social life and customs.; Jewish day schools.; Jews -- Education.; Songbooks.; Ethnic schools.; Ethnicity.; Bilingualism.; Education -- Bilingual.; Teaching.; Jews -- History.; Children's literature, Yiddish.; Education, Cooperative.; Minorities -- Study and teaching.; Community schools.; Linguistic minorities.; Education.; Yiddish language.; Krow-Lucal, Martha G.; Friends of the Secular Yiddish Schools in North America; Fishman, Gella Schweid
- Series 1. Yiddish school files
  - Barkan, Hershl. Souvenir, Anniversary and Graduation Journals., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Administrative / Organizational Materials
  - Bender, Sabell. School Performances and Scripts for School Plays, 1963-1965; Accession no. xxxx-xxx (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Play script "Treasures of a Century". 23 pp., first page missing. Three classic Yiddish authors (Peretz, Mendele and Sholem Aleichem) meet with some twentieth-century children and tell them stories of modern Yiddish culture and the events surrounding their grandparents' lives. Includes stories of Hershele Ostropolier and poems/songs by Rosenfeld, Bovshover, Edelshtat, M. Birnbaum and Z. Weinper. English with some Yiddish and some transliteration. Original. -- 3 1/2 x 5 card announcing "35th Annual Concert of the Los Angeles Kindershules and Mittelshules. 'Treasures sof a Century (A Pageant Celebrating 100 Years of Modern Yiddish Literature)'" by Sabell Bender. Yiddish and English. Original. -- Wilshire-Ebell Theatre printed program, a publication of the Playgoer Group of theatre magazines. Events taking place in the W-E Theatre during May, 1963, including Jewish Children's Schools Concert program, pp. 21-28. Short description of school curriculum on p. 28. English. Original. -- Bilingual leaflet entitled "Annual Concert of the Jewish Children's Schools of Los Angeles. A performance of 'Our Proud Heritage (A Pageant of Jewish History)'" by Sabell Bender. Yiddish and English. Original.
    School Performances and Scripts for School Plays; IWO, Ordn
  - Barkan, Hershl. Tributes., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Tributes and Anniversary Celebrations
  - Bender, Sabell. School and Affiliated-Organization Newsletters and Bulletins, 1968-1969; Accession no. xxxx-xxx (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Los Angeles Mittleshule "Her Zikh Tsu," Feb. 1968 and Feb. 1969. Announcements of events and meetings. English. Mimeo original.
    School and Affiliated-Organization Newsletters and Bulletins; Bender, Sabell
  - Barkan, Hershl. Student Writing, Published and Unpublished., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Student Writings: Published and Unpublished
  - Bates-Bracket, Ellen. Affiliated Organizations: Documents., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bates-Bracket, Ellen. Holiday Materials., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Holiday Materials
  - Bell, Ann Serkin. Souvenir, Anniversary and Graduation Journals., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Souvenir Journals
  - Bell, Ann Serkin. Photographs., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Photographs.
  - Bell, Ann Serkin. Outreach/Publicity Regarding Schools., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    School Publicity: Newspaper Clippings
  - Benyas, Shirley Z. Student Writing, Published and Unpublished., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Benyas, Shirley Z. Photographs., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Benyas, Shirley Z. School Performances., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    School Performances and Scripts for School Plays
  - Benyas, Shirley Z. Affiliated Organizations: Documents., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Benyas, Shirley Z. Holiday Materials., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Burstein, Esther. Administrative/Organizational Materials., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Burstein, Esther. Informational Material: History, Philosophy, Curriculum of Yiddish Schools, Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Informational Material: History, Philosophy, Curriculum of Schools
  - Burstein, Esther. Photographs., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Burstein, Esther. Souvenir Journal., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Caro, Beatrice. Personal Memoirs., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Memoirs: Published and Unpublished
  - Colker, Itzik. Student Publications., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Cymerman, Hadassah. School and Affiliated Organizations: Newsletters and Bulletins., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    School and Affiliated-Organization Newsletters and Bulletins
  - Drachler, Nakhmen. Outreach/Publicity, Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Drachler, Nakhmen. Informational Material Re Yiddish Schools, Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Drachler, Nakhmen. Souvenir Journals., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Epner, Daniel. Souvenir Journals [1 of 2], Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Epner, Daniel. Souvenir Journals [1 of 2], Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Friedman, Hinde S. Student Writings., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Friedman, Hinde S. Publications for Children., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Publications for Children
  - Friedman, Hinde S. Student Publications., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Friedman, Hinde S. Souvenir Journals., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Friedman, Sarah. Minutes and Reports; PTA., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Friedman, Sarah. Affiliated Organizations: Docs., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Friedman, Shulamis L. Souvenir Journal., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Goldstein, Ruth. Photos., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Grackin, Herman. Student Writings., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Grackin, Herman. Souvenir Journals., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Grackin, Herman. Diplomas, Report cards, Graduation announcements and Certificates., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Diplomas, Report Cards, Graduation Announcements & Certificates
  - Grackin, Herman. Informational Materials: History, Philosophy, Curriculum of Yiddish Schools., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Grackin, Herman. Affiliated Organizations: Documents., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Grackin, Herman. Photos., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Grackin, Herman. Archival Collections from Other Institutions., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Archival Collections of Other Institutions
  - Greenspan, Rose, S. Photos., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Greenspan, Rose, S. Student Writings, Published and Unpublished., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Greenspan, Rose, S. Affiliated Organizations., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Greenspan, Rose, S. Administrative/Organizational Materials., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Hartman, Hershl. Administrative /Organizational Materials., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Hartman, Hershl. Souvenir Journals., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Hartman, Hershl. Curricular Materials for Teachers., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Curriculum Material for Teachers
  - Hartman, Hershl. Curricular Materials for Teachers, continued., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Harwood, Naomi. Souvenir Journals., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Kahn, Leybl. Student Notebooks and Class Notes., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Student Notebooks and Class Notes
  - Kahn, Leybl. Examinations, Elementary and High School., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Examinations: Elementary and High School
  - Kahn, Taybl. School Publicity: Newspaper Clippings., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Kahn, Taybl. Holiday Materials., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Kahn, Taybl. School Publicity: Newspaper Clippings., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Kahn, Taybl. Souvenir Journals [1 of 2], Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Kahn, Taybl. Souvenir Journals [2 of 2], Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Klein, Mendl-Dovid. Souvenir Journals [1 of 3], Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Klein, Mendl-Dovid. Souvenir Journals [2 of 3], Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Klein, Mendl-Dovid. Souvenir Journals [3 of 3], Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Klein, Mendl-Dovid. Souvenir Journals and Graduation Programs., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Klein, Mendl-Dovid. School and Organization Newsletters and Bulletins., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Klein, Mendl-Dovid. Scripts for School Plays., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Klein, Mendl-Dovid. School Publicity: Newspaper Clippings re WC Schhol andandx0023;3, 1949-58., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Klein, Mendl-Dovid. Holiday Materials., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Klein, Mendl-Dovid. Student Publications., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Klein, Mendl-Dovid. Materials for Teaching Yiddish to Adults., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Pedagogical Materials: Yiddish Language
  - Klein, Mendl-Dovid. List of Names, Addresses, School Board Members., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Krow, Judith. Diploma., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Krow-Lucal, Martha. Curricular Materials for Teachers., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Krow-Lucal, Martha. Souvenir Journals., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Krow-Lucal, Martha. School Performances and Scripts for School Plays., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Krow-Lucal, Martha. Songs: Music and Lyrics., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Songs: Music and Lyrics
  - Krow-Lucal, Martha. Yiddish Camps: Boiberik and Kinderland., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Yiddish Summer Camp Materials
  - Krow-Lucal, Martha. Textbooks and Workbooks., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Krow-Lucal, Martha. Outreach/Publicity Regarding Yiddish/Jewish Schools., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Krow-Lucal, Martha. Holiday Materials., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Krow-Lucal, Martha. Diplomas, Report Cards, Graduation Announcements., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Krupit, Pearl. Pedagogical Materials: Jewish History., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Pedagogical Materials: Jewish History
  - Krupit, Pearl. Publications for Children., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Krupit, Pearl. Administrative/Organizational Materials., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Krupit, Pearl. Songs: Music and Lyrics., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Krupit, Pearl. Holiday Materials., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Krupit, Pearl. Pedagogical Materials: Yiddish Language., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Krupit, Pearl. Pedagogical Materials: Yiddish Literature., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Pedagogical Materials: Yiddish Literature
  - Kugler, Israel. Informational Material: History, Philosophy, Curriculum of Yiddish Schools., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Levine, Chane. Archival Collections of Other Institutions., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Kryshtal, Chana. Pedagogical Materials: Yiddish Language., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Levine, Merke. Songs: Music and Lyrics., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Levine, Merke. Creative Arts., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Creative Arts
  - Levine, Merke. Pedagogical Materials: Yiddish Literature., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Levine, Merke. Publications for Children., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Levine, Merke. Examinations: Elementary and High School., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Levine, Merke. Pedagogical Materials: Yiddish Language., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Levine, Merke. Outreach/Publicity Regarding Schools., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Margolis, Chassie. School and Affiliated Organization Newsletters and Bulletins., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Margolis, Chassie. Curriculum Materials for Teachers., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Margolis, Chassie. Souvenir, Anniversary and Graduation Journals., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Mark, Hershl. Photographs., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Mark, Hershl. Souvenir, Anniversary and Graduation Journals., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Messinger, Miriam. Photographs., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Messinger, Miriam. Diplomas, Report Cards, Graduation Announcements., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Messinger, Miriam. School and Affiliated Organization Newsletters and Bulletins., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Olitsky, Mattis. Informational Material: History, Philosophy, Curriculum of Yiddish Schools., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Olitsky, Mattis. Souvenir, Anniversary and Graduation Journals., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Ovshinsky, Herb. Personal Memoirs., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Pinkson, Ruth and Ray. Photographs., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Pinkson, Ruth and Ray. School Performances., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Pinkson, Ruth and Ray. Souvenir, Anniversary and Graduation Journals., Accession no. 1995-157 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Pinkson, Ruth and Ray. Informational Material: History, Philosophy, Curriculum of Yiddish Schools., Accession no. 1995-157 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Pinkson, Ruth and Ray. Archival Collections of Other Institutions., Accession no. 1995-157 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Pinkson, Ruth and Ray. School and Affiliated Organization Newsletters and Bulletins., Accession no. 1995-157 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Revsin, Gerry. Informational Material: History, Philosophy, Curriculum of Yiddish Schools., Accession no. 1995-157 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Schaefer, Lyvia. School Publicity - Newspaper Clippings., Accession no. 1995-157 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Shak, Gella M. Student Writings., Accession no. 1995-157 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Shak, Gella M. Holiday Materials., Accession no. 1995-157 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Shak, Gella M. Diplomas, Report Cards, Graduation Announcements., Accession no. 1995-157 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Shak, Gella M. Photographs., Accession no. 1995-157 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Shak, Gella M. Souvenir, Anniversary and Graduation Journals., Accession no. 1995-157 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Shapiro, Ray. Souvenir, Anniversary and Graduation Journals., Accession no. 1995-157 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Benny and Lily Sherman, donor: Herman Foster. Affiliated Organizations: Documents., Accession no. 1995-157 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Estate of Benny and Lily Sherman, donor: Herman Foster. Pedagogical Materials: Holocaust., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Pedagogical Materials: Holocaust
  - Estate of Benny and Lilly Sherman, donor: Herman Foster. Pedagogical Materials: Yiddish language., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Estate of Benny and Lilly Sherman, donor: Herman Foster. Songs: Music and lyrics., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Estate of Benny and Lilly Sherman, donor: Herman Foster. Outreach/Publicity Re Schools., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Estate of Benny and Lilly Sherman, donor: Herman Foster. Affiliate Organizations: Documents., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Estate of Benny and Lilly Sherman, donor: Herman Foster. Publications for Children., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Estate of Benny and Lilly Sherman, donor: Herman Foster. Administrative/Organizational Materials., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Siegel, Tsippy. Informational Material: History, Philosophy, Curriculum of Yiddish Schools., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Siegel, Tsippy. Personal Memoirs, Published and Unpublished., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Simon, Madeline. Souvenir Journals., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Simon, Madeline. School Performances and Scripts for School Plays., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Steele, Joseph. Photographs., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Stonehill, Lee. Informational Material: History, Philosophy and Curriculum of Yiddish Schools., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Stonehill, Lee. Songs: Music and Lyrics., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Stonehill, Lee. Administrative/Organizational Materials., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Stonehill, Lee. Outreach/Publicity Re Schools., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Stonehill, Lee. Photographs., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Stonehill, Lee. School Performances and Scripts for School Plays., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Stonehill, Lee. School and Affiliated Newsletters and Bulletins., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Wagner, Sylvia. Personal Memoirs, Published and Unpublished., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Wanamaker, Edith. Affiliated Organizations: Documents., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Wanamaker, Edith. Informational Material: History, Philosophy, Curriculum of Yiddish Schools., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Wanamaker, Edith. Souvenir Journals., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Weiss, Sari. Personal Memoirs, Published and Unpublished., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Weitzel, Sandra. Diplomas, Report Cards, Graduation Announcements and Certificates., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Wilen, Rina M. Pedagogical Materials: Yiddish Language., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Young, Mildred B. Photographs., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Young, Mildred B. Personal Memoirs, Published and Unpublished., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Zuckerman, Harold. Informational Material: History, Philosophy, Curriculum of Yiddish Schools., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Itzkowitz, Fay. Pedagogical Materials: Yiddish Literature., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Itzkowitz, Fay. Informational Materials: History, Philosophy, Curriculum of Yiddish Schools., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Itzkowitz, Fay. Yiddish Camp Materials., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Itzkowitz, Fay. Pedagogical Materials: Yiddish Language., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Itzkowitz, Fay. Holiday Materials., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Itzkowitz, Fay. Songs: Music and Lyrics., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Itzkowitz, Fay. Curriculum Materials for Teachers., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Itzkowitz, Fay. Souvenir Journals., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Itzkowitz, Fay. Pedagogical Materials: Holocaust., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Margolis, Chassie. School Performances and Scripts for School Plays., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Margolis, Chassie. Songs: Music and Lyrics., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Foner, Henry. Outreach/Publicity Re Schools., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Foner, Henry. Photographs., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Foner, Henry. Holiday Materials, Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Foner, Henry. Songs: Music and Lyrics., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Foner, Henry. School Performances and Scripts for School Plays., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Foner, Henry. Souvenir Journals., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Feinberg, Cantor Sheldon. Non-Print Media: Holiday Materials., Accession no. 1995-263 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Feinstein, Roberta. Pedagogical Materials: Yiddish Language., Accession no. 1995-264 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Feinstein, Roberta. Souvenir Journals., Accession no. 1995-264 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Halpern, Rita. Holiday Material., Accession no. 1995-265 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Moskowitz, May. School and Affiliated Organization Newsletters and Bulletins., Accession no. 1995-266 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Moskowitz, May. School and Affiliated Organization Newsletters and Bulletins., Accession no. 1995-266 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Moskowitz, May. School and Affiliated Organization Newsletters and Bulletins., Accession no. 1995-266 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Moskowitz, May. School and Affiliated Organization Newsletters and Bulletins., Accession no. 1995-266 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Moskowitz, May. Personal Memoirs: Published and Unpublished., Accession no. 1995-266 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Moskowitz, May. Songs: Music and Lyrics., Accession no. 1995-266 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Moskowitz, May. Holiday Materials., Accession no. 1995-266 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Moskowitz, May. Curriculum Materials for Teachers., Accession no. 1995-266 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Moskowitz, May. Secular Bar-Bas/Bat Mitzvah., Accession no. 1995-266 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Moskowitz, May. Administrative/Organizational Materials., Accession no. 1995-266 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Moskowitz, May. School Publicity: Newspaper Clippings., Accession no. 1995-266 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Moskowitz, May. Informational Materials: History, Philosophy, Curriculum of Yiddish Schools., Accession no. 1995-266 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Moskowitz, May. Informational Materials: History, Philosophy, Curriculum of Yiddish Schools., Accession no. 1995-266 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Moskowitz, May. Affiliated Organizations: Documents., Accession no. 1995-266 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Moskowitz, May. School Performances and Scripts for School Plays., Accession no. 1995-266 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Moskowitz, May. Pedagogical Materials: Israel., Accession no. 1995-266 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Pedagogical Materials: Israel
  - Weinstein, Sidney. School Performances and Scripts for School Plays., Accession no. 1996-087 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Weinstein, Sidney. Pedagogical Materials: Yiddish Literature., Accession no. 1996-087 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Weinstein, Sidney. Souvenir Journals., Accession no. 1996-087 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Weinstein, Sidney. Creative Arts., Accession no. 1996-087 (Box 10, Folder 11)